E-mail: JamesLeeWeller@Gmail.com

#### **Personal Statement**

I recently completed my M.Sc. in forensic psychology. I am keen to pursue a career in data analytics and research. As part of my B.Sc. and M.Sc. I completed modules for research, advanced research, and data analysis. Mainly focusing on planning, data collection, cleansing, manipulate, visualisation, hypothesis testing, and reporting. I am skilled in both quantitative (numerical and categorical data) and qualitative (face-to-face interviews). I have been using IBM SPSS for five years. I am self-taught in R programming language (R and Rstudio) having been using R for over 2 years. I am also skilled in data analysis using Python having been using python for over a year. I have a working knowledge of SQL.

I have excellent communication skills working for four years in a customer orientated role helping customers face-to-face and over the telephone. I am highly skilled in solving problems in diverse and stressful environments. This has allowed me to develop a confident, enthusiastic and approachable persona. I have an excellent ability to work within a team and to work on my own initiative. I also have excellent leadership skill running a weekly student-led session for first-year undergraduate students and I am a member of the Institute of Leadership & Management. I was a committee member of a society at university, a role that involved organising and planning events.

# **Education & Qualifications**

2016 - 2017	University of Bedfordshire M.Sc. Forensic Psychology (Distinction)
2013 - 2016	University of Bedfordshire B.Sc. (Hons) Psychology and Criminal Behaviour (First)
2009 - 2012	BHASVIC Sixth Form College, Brighton 4 A-Level Grade B - D Including Psychology, Archaeology, and Finance 8 GCSE's Grades A* – D Including English, Maths, Science, and Finance

### **Professional Experience**

Design asylum (October 2016 - Present)

Warehouse operative

Duties:

- Ensure that correct stock is picked
- Operating the till and processing orders
- Ensuring that all safety precautions are met and the work areas are safe
- Working to strict deadlines for shipments
- Unloading deliveries

Self-Employed (July 2007 – July 2014)

Mechanical Mate and Mechanical Improver

Duties:

- Working independently without supervision
- Teamwork
- Ensuring that all safety precautions are met
- Maintaining cleanliness at all time around work areas
- Moving material around the site
- Working under pressure and time constraints

Telegen UK (March 2007 to May 2007)

Telesales agent

Duties:

- Communicating with customers
- Promoting products to a potential customer
- Offering advice based on the customer's needs
- Answering question and queries
- Asking the customer relevant question to ensure suitability of products
- Ensuring that the customer receives the best possible service

## Voluntary Work/Work Experience

University of Bedfordshire February 2016 - March 2016

Teaching assistant

#### Duties:

- Led class discussion and debates
- Running activities in tutorials
- Planning tutorials/activities
- Learning lesson plans/material
- Engaging with students

University of Bedfordshire October 2014 - March 2016

PAL Leader/Senior PAL leader

### Duties:

- Teamwork
- Planning activities/session each week
- Problem-solving
- Working independently
- Working with new students
- Answering question
- Mentoring students

AGE UK January 2012 - May 2012

IT Drop-in-Centre Assistant

### Duties:

- Assisting users
- Teaching basic IT skills
- Giving demonstration
- Working independently
- Problem-solving
- Answering question and queries
- Using Microsoft Word and Excel

# **Technical Skills**

- Microsoft office suite (10 years)
- Google office suite (5 years)
- OS: Windows, OSX, Linux (7+ years)
- Training in Leadership, Coaching, & Mentoring (Institute of Leadership & Management)
- www.linkedin.com/in/James-Weller

# **Statistical & Programming Languages:**

- Portfolio (https://jameslweller.github.io/Portfolio.html)
- Quantitative & Qualitative Research Method
- IBM SPSS (5 years)
- R statistical programming and data visualisation (ggplot2, dplyr, psych, car, etc)
- Data Analysis in Python (Pandas, matplotlib, Seaborn, scikit-learn, numpy, scipy, etc)
- Jupyter notebook
- Basic Knowledge of SAS & SQL

### Awards

- BHASVIC Three Student commendation 2010
- BHASVIC IP student of the year 2011
- University of Bedfordshire PAL leader special commendation 2015 and 2016
- University of Bedfordshire Health and Social Sciences Faculty PAL Leader Award 2016
- University of Bedfordshire Jubilee Scholarship for postgraduate studies 2016